Thai Le

CONTACT



thaile314@gmail.com



https://thai-d-le.github.io/projects.html



650.309.8863

EDUCATION

University of Washington, Seattle, WA (Dec 2014)
PhD, Biomedical Health Informatics
Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD (2009)
BS, Biomedical Engineering, Mathematics

Relevant Coursework

Usability Research Survey Research Methods Web Programming Bayesian Statistics for Social Sciences Data Structure and Algorithms Machine Learning and Al

Honors

Student Editorial Board for *Journal of the American Medical Informatics Association*National Library of Medicine Fellowship Award
National Merit Scholarship Award

SKILLS

Technical: Statistical Analysis (R)

Web Development (HTML, CSS, JS)

Programming (Python, Java)

Database Management (SQL, Access)
Data Visualization (D3, Prefuse)
Remote Testing (UserTesting)

User Research: Focus Groups

Card Sorts and Tree Testing

Think-Aloud Studies Contextual Inquiries Heuristic Evaluations

Survey/Questionnaire Development

Conjoint/MaxDiff Analysis

Tools: Qualtrics

Optimal Workshop

Sawtooth Tableau Figma

Overview

I am looking for an engaging research position that integrates both quantitative and qualitative methodologies to create enjoyable and intuitive user experiences. I come from an HCI focused PhD with over 5 years of experience as a research scientist. I complement this with 10 years of industry experience as a mixed methods user researcher.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Pinterest (Staff User Researcher)

Feb 2022 – Current

I lead research for Ads Measurement and Analytics, helping enterprise advertisers understand the value of their marketing efforts on Pinterest.

Google (Sr User Researcher/Manager)

Aug 2017 - Jan 2022

Lead user researcher on the Google Domains team, helping small businesses grow on Google. I combine qualitative approaches, surveys, log analysis, and A/B testing to provide a holistic understanding of the product while managing a team of 2 other junior researchers.

Amazon Web Services (Lead User Researcher)

Jun 2014 – Aug 2017

Lead user researcher on the Amazon Web Services (AWS) Marketing Design Team. As the first user researcher on the team, I established best practice principles for conducting user research, evangelizing its impact to stakeholders. I integrated qualitative lab studies, site metrics, A/B testing, and surveys to identify gaps in the user experience.

University of Washington (Research Scientist)

Sep 2010 - Dec 2014

Led multiple independent research projects centered on applications of health information technology to support older adult wellness. I designed and evaluated health visualizations for older adults, conducted usability testing on the navigation of health interfaces, and designed, deployed, and analyzed a statewide survey of older adult health information seeking behavior.

Amazon.com Inc. (User Research Intern)

Mar 2013 – Aug 2013

Conducted usability studies on Amazon.com's retail site. I led user testing for the rollout of a new book club sign-up program through Amazon Publishing. In addition, I identified limitations to currently available web based tree testing tools and developed an alternative web tool. This was deployed in a survey of 600 customers to evaluate navigational taxonomy.

SELECT PUBLICATIONS

1. **Le T**, Reeder B, Chung J, Thompson H, Demiris G. Design of Smart Home Sensor Visualizations for Older Adults. *Technology and Health Care*. 2014; 22(4):657-66.

2. **Le T**, Chaudhuri S, Chung J, Thompson H, Demiris G. Tree Testing of Hierarchical Menu Structures for Health Applications. *Journal of Biomedical Informatics*. 2014;49:198-205.